Scott Hebert

Scott.phebert@yahoo.com | ♠ https://github.com/spark1eaf | ♠ Lafayette, Louisiana 70508 | https://scottphebert.com | ♠ https://linkedin.com/in/scott-hebert-9b1789240

Professional Summary

Software developer passionate about expanding my skillset. Experienced with backend development, specifically working with Spring Boot and HCL Commerce frameworks. I place high value in effective communication and efficiency.

Skills

Languages: Java, JavaScript, C++, C#, Python, HTML, CSS, SQL

Frameworks: Spring Boot, HCL Commerce, ReactJS

Technologies & Tools: JSP, Postman, Azure DevOps, Selenium, Cypress

Work Experience

Technical Consultant, Backend Developer

June 2022 - Present

Perficient Inc.

Client: Fortune 500 Construction Equipment Manufacturer

- Worked with four separate teams throughout time on the project across varying areas of an E-Commerce parts site.
- Participated in backend Java development on a monolithic application leveraging technologies such as Spring Boot, HCL Commerce, JSP, and Oracle SQL.
- Implemented Novel Functionality allowing users from various countries to shop with company's card payment system, allowing users to make purchases through a line of credit.
- Assisted with migration from SOLR to LUCID for applications search API.
- Took part in creation of Spring Boot Microservices based on legacy code along with writing Apigee contracts for the newly created services.
- Assisted in research and adjustments with the goal of attaining compliance with security assessment criteria.

Outbound Loader Oct 2013 - May 2021

Sysco Wholesale Distribution

- · Check quality of outgoing products.
- Ensured departure times were met.
- Secured products for safe shipment to customers.
- Regulated the staging of outgoing product at the proper locations for related routes.
- Assisted other dock employees with any process issues as section's most senior employee.

Supply Administration Specialist

Apr 2013 - Nov 2019

United States Marine Corps Reserve

- · Lead peers in accomplishing logistical goals on various projects.
- · Assisted with unit audits.
- Conducted gear issues and disposals.
- · Tracked on hand equipment through GCSS system.
- · Acted as a mentor for junior Marines.

Education

University of Louisiana Lafayette

Aug 2017 - Apr 2022

B.S. Computer Science

Travel

Negotiable